https://www.hiram.edu/privacy-policy/

Skip to content
Hiram Advisory: COVID-19 Advisory Alert System and Dashboard - Current Level 2 (Orange) Learn More
Privacy Policy
Home
Privacy Policy
Hiram College Privacy Policy and Terms of Use
This is the website of Hiram College, located at 11715 Garfield Rd, Hiram, Ohio 44234.
Website administrators can be reached via email at collegerelations@hiram.edu or by telephone at 330.569.3211.
If you receive email communications from Hiram College and do not want to receive email from us in the future, please let us know by emailing collegerelations@hiram.edu or clicking the “unsubscribe” link at the bottom of the email. We do not share email addresses with outside organizations.
The Privacy Policy
The Hiram College Privacy Policy was developed as an extension of our commitment to combine the highest quality products and services with the highest level of integrity. It is designed to assist you in understanding how we collect, use and safeguard the personal information you provide and to help you in making informed decisions when using our site, products and services. This Privacy Policy will be continually assessed against new technologies, business practices and our customers’ needs
As described below, some of your personally identifiable information will be used by us for the purpose of contacting you regarding the information that you have requested. By using the website, you expressly consent to our use of your personal information and also to the disclosure to and use of this information in our efforts to contact you and for continued marketing effort by the College and agents charged with communicating with our customers and potential customers. You acknowledge that communications to, from and through this website are not confidential. You agree that by submitting communications through this website, no confidential, fiduciary, contractually implied or other relationship is created between you and this website other than pursuant to this Privacy Policy.
The college adheres to legal requirements prescribed by relevant statutes, such as the (FERPA) Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974. Our FERPA document notice may be found online.
What information is collected?
Anonymous information
Hiram College may collect and store from website visitors: referrer pages, date/time stamps, pages requested, browser and computer information, user agent, headers, files downloaded and any errors encountered.
Personal information
Hiram College may collect and store personal identifying information, such as name, username, email address, IP address, social network account information and activity, mailing address and telephone numbers.
How is the information collected?
Hiram College may use network, server and browser technologies to collect website visitor information, including:
Cookies: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTTP_cookie
Scripts: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/HTML_scripting
Server logs: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Server_log
Custom URL parameters: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Query_string
Tracking images: https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Web_beacon
Information and correspondence submitted voluntarily by visitors via forms, comments, chats, etc.
Why is the information collected?
Hiram College collects website visitor information to: better serve audiences by optimizing and personalizing visitor experiences in both digital and physical spaces, manage a visitor relationship with the College, foster/promote further communications, gauge communication effectiveness, gain insights into user behavior and preferences, track interests, identify errors and issues and conduct market research.
Hiram College does not sell or rent website visitor information and does not share website visitor information except as compelled by law.
Is the information secure?
We utilize encryption/security software to safeguard the confidentiality of personal information we collect. This software provides a limited degree of protection against unauthorized access or disclosure, as well as accidental loss, alteration or destruction.
Third Parties
Hiram College may contract and partner with external third parties to place ads on websites not affiliated with the College. These non-affiliated sites may send and share visitor information and browsing behavior, collected in accordance with their own privacy policies, with Hiram College. These third-party websites may also display advertisements to previous visitors of the Hiram College site.
Disclaimer Regarding Outside Web Sites
The Hiram College website contains links to other independently run web sites within the Hiram College network and to some sites outside the hiram.edu domain. Hiram College is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such web sites.
Opting out
Hiram College respects the privacy decisions of its constituents. Website visitors may choose to not have data collected by Hiram College websites. The Federal Trade Commission provides guides for protecting the privacy of children visiting websites: https://www.consumer.ftc.gov/topics/protecting-kids-online
Do not track
Most modern web browsers provide a user privacy setting, which when enabled, informs websites to disable its information collection methods. More information:
https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Do_Not_Track
Responsible Internet advertisers have tools to opt-out or control advertisements and tracking:
http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/
https://choice.microsoft.com/
https://support.google.com/ads/answer/2662922?hl=en
https://www.facebook.com/help/769828729705201/
Minors/Children
Hiram College does not knowingly collect website visitor information from children or minors as defined by the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA).
Questions
Please email: collegerelations@hiram.edu with any questions about this privacy statement.
We use cookies to provide you with a better experience.
By continuing to use this site you agree to our use of cookies. I Understand
